<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Blockchain on Marshall Vyletel</title>
    <link>/tags/blockchain/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Blockchain on Marshall Vyletel</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>This work is licensed under a Creative Commons Attribution-NonCommercial 4.0 International License.</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 04 Jun 2021 08:07:28 -0400</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/tags/blockchain/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Quantifying Experience - Introduction</title>
      <link>/posts/quantifying-experience-introduction/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 04 Jun 2021 08:07:28 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/quantifying-experience-introduction/</guid>
      <description>#writing+projects/essays/complete
Introduction This essay is part self-exploration and part detached observation. I have been actively seeking full-time opportunities in the world that can give me a bit of financial freedom, and doing so has forced me to engage with some self-honesty.
This whole process has been unexpectedly difficult. To be totally honest, I kind of naively expected that with my education history, I would be able to land an entry level role rather quickly, but this was a pretty flawed assumption.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Blockchain Initial Thoughts</title>
      <link>/posts/blockchain-initial-ideation/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 02 Jun 2021 00:24:52 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/blockchain-initial-ideation/</guid>
      <description>#writing+projects/essays/complete
Let’s just jump right in.
 Why? I want to be clear about my intentions with diving into this world completely so as not to get caught up in the obvious wealth generating potential. I think that with good work and ideas, the money should naturally take care of itself.
While my knowledge is obviously somewhat limited, I still feel confident enough to posit a few research avenues and general philosophical underpinnings that should sustain my appetite to research and continue finding ways to add value.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
