<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
	<channel>
		<title>Posts on Marshall Vyletel</title>
		<link>//vyletel.eth.link/posts/</link>
		<description>Recent content in Posts on Marshall Vyletel</description>
		<generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
		<language>en-us</language>
		<copyright>This work is licensed under a Creative Commons Attribution-NonCommercial 4.0 International License.</copyright>
		<lastBuildDate>Wed, 02 Jun 2021 00:24:52 -0400</lastBuildDate>
		<atom:link href="//vyletel.eth.link/posts/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
		
		<item>
			<title>Blockchain Initial Thoughts</title>
			<link>//vyletel.eth.link/posts/blockchain-initial-ideation/</link>
			<pubDate>Wed, 02 Jun 2021 00:24:52 -0400</pubDate>
			
			<guid>//vyletel.eth.link/posts/blockchain-initial-ideation/</guid>
			<description>#writing+projects/essays/complete
Let’s just jump right in.
 Why? I want to be clear about my intentions with diving into this world completely so as not to get caught up in the obvious wealth generating potential. I think that with good work and ideas, the money should naturally take care of itself.
While my knowledge is obviously somewhat limited, I still feel confident enough to posit a few research avenues and general philosophical underpinnings that should sustain my appetite to research and continue finding ways to add value.</description>
			<content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>#writing+projects/essays/complete</p>
<p>Let’s just jump right in.</p>
<hr>
<h2 id="why">Why?</h2>
<p>I want to be clear about my intentions with diving into this world completely so as not to get caught up in the obvious wealth generating potential. I think that with good work and ideas, the money should naturally take care of itself.</p>
<p>While my knowledge is obviously somewhat limited, I still feel confident enough to posit a few research avenues and general philosophical underpinnings that should sustain my appetite to research and continue finding ways to add value. I will expand on the following for now, but the main “things“ are:</p>
<ol>
<li>Value - How does value get determined in a decentralized system?</li>
<li>Markets - How do people actually get connected to one another to trade services and create novel markets across borders? Again, how does the value of a particular transaction get decided?</li>
<li>“Real World Translation” - How will this translate into life? How can this digital community-based system of decentralized financial (DeFi) tools take the value manifested online and transform it into things that really help people live? (Food, shelter, clothing, safety, general wealth, etc…)</li>
<li>Empowerment - How can this technology provide novel wealth generation opportunities to the individual by leveraging these three components above?</li>
</ol>
<p>Essentially, my obsession with this technology is in the last question. I want to understand how these decentralized ecosystems can empower anyone to find a community or others to connect with that need what they can uniquely offer. Similarly, I want to understand the flow of value and resources to patch up leaks to ensure an efficient distribution of resources in such a way for people to tap into communal wealth without necessarily having to be a developer on the chain, or be a “builder” themselves. This may be a pipe dream, but it feels like this technology is really a wealth distribution mechanism. With every individual having some semblance of power in a system, everyone is motivated to increase its value.</p>
<p>I want to understand how to create mechanisms that work WITH deep-rooted human behavior (selfishness, desire for power and wealth, status, desire to be a part of something meaningful, desires for connection, etc…) to empower individuals to be able to truly take control of their lives. The future of work is not working.</p>
<p><strong>The possibility exists for every person to work for themselves, do what they love to do, and live a healthy, complete life. All that is missing is the knowledge of how best to distribute resources and value in a way that doesn’t provide a ceiling to the limits of personal wealth, but also allows those with nothing to be valuable players in the global economy.</strong></p>
<p>The truth is, money sits at the root of freedom in society. If you have wealth, you have freedom. While money doesn’t buy you freedom from your personal problems or necessarily translate into happiness, it is the single most important aspect of being alive and healthy these days. I see no way around that. Point is, it is much easier to become a better human if you know where your next meal is coming, where you can sleep, and if you know that if you want to have some experience, you can afford to make it happen.  There really is no reason that everyone shouldn’t have access to these things. There are limits, obviously. We live in a world of scarcity, and not everyone can live in a Beverly Hills mansion. There just isn’t enough space. But honestly, everyone should be able to live safely, where they want to, and know that their basic human needs are going to be met without question. This is possible. Those who want more should be able to make that happen by adding more value, but not everyone wants that.</p>
<p>So to be clear, I want to explore the concept of wealth and value in a decentralized environment to more easily empower individuals to create and find their way to wherever they want to be in the social hierarchy.  This utopian view obviously will require SOME time sacrifices on the part of the individual, but we should be able to find ways to decrease the suffering from that sacrifice. Let’s go deeper.</p>
<hr>
<h2 id="value">Value</h2>
<p>The point of this paper is not to solve these questions for myself, but rather to crystallize and clarify the questions themselves. The most important of which is the question of how value is manifested in this system. My understanding is that there are a few ways to understand this. Obviously, we value the things that bring us the experiences we desire: not being hungry, doing meaningful work, experiencing art, having a community, and having fun (amongst others). Now, in the decentralized world, this seems to be dealt with through the concept of legitimacy. If we decide that something is a legitimate manifestation of the thing we want, we value it.</p>
<p>To elucidate this further, we can use the recent example of Elon Musk considering whether to create an NFT of a tweet of his. As Vitalik points out in a recent blog post, if Elon Musk himself does this and sells it, it would be worth millions. But if I do this of the SAME tweet, the value dramatically decreases because it is not as “legitimate” in the eyes of the community. This feels intuitively true, but is really just a manifestation of this human need to capture a somewhat fake “essence” in things. It’s a further abstraction of the idea that if I tell you this baseball was the one hit on Babe Ruth’s first homerun, you will be dramatically engaged with it. It takes on a power. But then if I tell you “No wait, this is actually my kid’s baseball from practice yesterday”, it is worthless even though nothing about the ball has changed. This is a phenomenally human quality that is both beautiful and important, but can cause dramatic issues in an economy. We value things in particularly strange ways, and this contributes to a massive misallocation of resources away from things that matter more strongly, like having a safe home in a good area, or access to healthy food and clean drinking water. That is why we both hate billionaires and want to be them. We see their “obvious” misallocation of wealth towards things like fast cars and incredible homes, but we also recognize that if we had the chance, it’s likely most of us would do the same.</p>
<p>The question becomes: How might it be possible to take advantage of this dichotomy to capture our value systems and distribute resources most effectively? Should we really just rely on those generating the most wealth to be altruistic in their usage of it? I’m not sure that is something we can rely on for many reasons. For one, this has been a possibility for a long time, but we still have millions of homeless people and incredibly impoverished communities. Secondly, how do we determine what is the most effective form of altruism (philosopher William MacAskill has pioneered the term “Effective Altruism” to explore this)? Third, how do we determine the most effective ways to support causes we deem are valuable, assuming our moral compass is well-calibrated?</p>
<p>In short, deciding what is valuable and what is not can be a fickle thing that will likely not provide any novel changes in human culture if we simply digitize and decentralize the current economic system. It gets better, but it isn’t solved.</p>
<p>Lastly, if someone wants to begin providing value, and is willing to offer good X for amount Y, but someone else is willing to offer it for Y-1, then we just see the same type of price gouging that takes advantage of inherently capitalist systems. How does one understand their own value, find, and connect with people who value them equally? Where are the opportunities for personal empowerment in this space?</p>
<hr>
<h2 id="markets">Markets</h2>
<p>This section should be shorter. The question is about market efficiency and participation. What I want to understand is how markets are created and operated so someone like me can find ways to participate in them. DeFi liquidity pools are an interesting example of this efficiency, but the barrier to entry, while technologically small, is still large if one wants to be effective in this. I’m not sure something needs to be solved here, just understood deeper so active and effective participation is possible. This is an area where I feel I could personally create value for myself, but I’m not exactly sure how that translates into a broader notion of community value.</p>
<hr>
<h2 id="translation">Translation</h2>
<p>Food, shelter, clothing, and community are the most fundamental aspects of well-being. These MUST be satisfied to some extent to make it possible for people to grow. They are the most basic of human needs and are an inextricable part of life. The question is quite simply, assuming one finds a way to create wealth for themselves in the global economy, how will we extend this to cover ways to maintain the basic needs in a similarly free and decentralized way? This is just something I want to explore, not another issue per se.</p>
<hr>
<h2 id="empowerment-and-conclusion">Empowerment and Conclusion</h2>
<p>To summarize, I am interested in personal wealth creation without the need to work for anyone but yourself. I want to find ways to take advantage of this global technology to work with the inherent proclivities of humanity to create markets that more efficiently allocate resources in line with these proclivities that translate into real world gain. Again, how people decide to use their wealth is up to them, but it seems that there is a creative solution that raises the tide to lift all boats. What could this look like?</p>
<p>I am not convinced yet that this new technology will solve the whale problem. It’s an obvious step in the right direction, but what I want to do is make creative markets that increase efficiency to make sure that every bit of our massive circulating resources finds its way to the individual who can find their particular niche in this economy. Right now, there are still so many instances of the biggest whales just getting bigger, and the technological barrier to entry is still massive. If you are not a developer or a skilled financier, how do you engage with this new tech?</p>
<p>Additionally, I haven’t even gone into the consensus algorithms that have obvious issues. As I write this, the two most popular are PoW (proof of work) and PoS (proof of stake). The former requires absolutely massive computational resources and complexity, and participating in the mining operation is really only limited to huge mining pools and therefore is at the mercy of groups that have the power to create them. Not that equitable. (China problem). Secondly, proof of stake will likely provide mining opportunities to those who have wealth in the system already, so that issue isn’t holistically solved. I understand that there is work to be done, but I just want to know which area is most ripe for myself. Lastly, I don’t see much talk of quantum computing in this world yet, and I’m curious as to how that will effect mining operations and the overall security of the network. Just a thought.</p>
<p>The point of this paper is just to briefly outline some small concerns and areas that I want to engage. Finding ways to do so and take steps in the right direction is a whole separate problem, that will likely only be solved by talking to as many people as possible and learning about what projects are solving which problems. I am still massively overwhelmed by this, but I’m just putting it out there.</p>
<p>Hopefully my intentions and curiosities with this new tech are clear. To make it even more clear, I am fully interested in personal wealth creation, market efficiency, and effective distribution of resources that takes advantage of our most natural proclivities to create an economy where everyone can join to the level that they want, and their are few ceilings on the potential for personal wealth. Uplifting individual creators, working for oneself/generating personal wealth, and meeting basic human needs. These are the things that excite me, and that I think have insane potential in this field. I just don’t know how yet.</p>
]]></content>
		</item>
		
	</channel>
</rss>
