<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Marshall Vyletel</title>
    <link>/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Marshall Vyletel</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>This work is licensed under a Creative Commons Attribution-NonCommercial 4.0 International License.</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 03 Jun 2021 11:47:44 -0400</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Trial2</title>
      <link>/posts/trial2/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 03 Jun 2021 11:47:44 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/trial2/</guid>
      <description>one more time to be extra sure.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Trial</title>
      <link>/posts/trial/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 03 Jun 2021 11:40:49 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/trial/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;m uploading this publicly to test a new hosting scheme for this website.
If it works, just know I am a genius.
If not, how are you reading this?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Spirituality</title>
      <link>/posts/spirituality/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 03 Jun 2021 08:53:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/spirituality/</guid>
      <description>The following is an essay I wrote to myself during late summer 2019. Since then, many things have changed, and I would probably re-write this essay with different language, but the overall ideas are still important to me. This piece forces me to take a step back and take the mental position of myself during the time of writing, and I always find a bit of peace in doing so. I think it is a valuable thing to re-read from time to time, so I&amp;rsquo;m putting it here in hopes that a piece of this will resonate with whoever visits the site.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Donate</title>
      <link>/donate/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 02 Jun 2021 12:38:12 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/donate/</guid>
      <description>If any of this resonates with you, please feel free to send some dolla bills.
I&amp;rsquo;m a broke 22 year old trying to find my way, so anything is appreciated.
Much love.
 Ethereum Addy ETH: 0xc278de7EA43c224FAC2525451C2AC1716386362E
 Patreon Link: https://www.patreon.com/user?u=56511877
 I want to incentivize you to donate somehow, but I will just assume you are doing it out of the deep kindness in your heart. Thanks, friend.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The OWL Project</title>
      <link>/projects/theowlproject/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 02 Jun 2021 01:59:30 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/projects/theowlproject/</guid>
      <description>What? Last year, I spent some time exploring the possibility of a news analysis ecosystem built on-chain.
Here is the exploratory whitepaper detailing the concept:
  Introduction There is an incomprehensible amount of information circulating on the internet. Over 4 billion humans connected to the web are constantly adding to the collection, each with their own implicit and explicit biases shaping how they perceive and propagate the information with which they interact.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>About</title>
      <link>/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 02 Jun 2021 00:33:59 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/about/</guid>
      <description>I never know what to write on these “About me” pages. It’s weird.
The basics:
 EDUCATION: Brown University ’20 Applied Mathematics and Computer Science HOMETOWN: Grosse Pointe Farms, Michigan CURRENT RESIDENCE: Boulder, Colorado CURRENT OCCUPATION: Part-Time Contractor work as Software Engineer for Rocket Alumni Solutions (Friend of a friend’s startup)  Aside from that, I make music. Not recently, because I’m broke and have turned my attention to finding a full-time job.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Blockchain Initial Thoughts</title>
      <link>/posts/blockchain-initial-ideation/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 02 Jun 2021 00:24:52 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/blockchain-initial-ideation/</guid>
      <description>#writing+projects/essays/complete
Let’s just jump right in.
 Why? I want to be clear about my intentions with diving into this world completely so as not to get caught up in the obvious wealth generating potential. I think that with good work and ideas, the money should naturally take care of itself.
While my knowledge is obviously somewhat limited, I still feel confident enough to posit a few research avenues and general philosophical underpinnings that should sustain my appetite to research and continue finding ways to add value.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
